MACHI MORI - CUSTOMS OFFICIAL
CLEAN UP EATING AREA
DARWIN OCE 720
COUNSELOR
MIDORI SUGIHARA
‎KEIICHIRO HAYAMI - IMMIGRATION OFFICIAL
Arima.
It's been a while, Hayami.
Are you doing well?
GATE 24 CONCEPT
What are you calling about?
I need a favor.
I want you to find a spy among your team.
What do you mean?
According to the Cabinet
Intelligence and Research Office,
the number of foreign subversives
entering the country has surged
over the past two months.
The past two months?
In short, ever since that gate opened.
Gate 24 has become
a backdoor for terrorists.
That's how they see it.
There's a spy in Gate 24?
I want you to find that spy.
Naturally, you'll be rewarded.
People are starting
to recognize your efforts.
Depending on the results,
I can back your return to headquarters.
I'm counting on you, Hayami.
Mori.
Oh my.
This stuff's great, isn't it?
It's really delicious.
Why have we never been here before?
-I would love to go here on my own.
-Huh?
What's up, Matsuyama?
-Is something wrong with that drawing?
-Isn't this
a drawing by Nobody?
JUNKO TAMAI - CUSTOMS OFFICIAL
Ah, you're right! It looks just like it.
What's Nobody?
You don't know?
It's the elusive masked artist
who flies around the world.
It's this.
Nobody is a pacifist artist
who paints artwork promoting peace
in war zones around the world.
Wait, then this drawing is theirs?
If it's real, wouldn't it
be worth a fortune?
Well, isn't the touch a bit different?
Nobody's lines are bolder
yet delicate, so to speak.
Listen to Mr. Expert over here.
Sorry, could you wipe that off?
What? Should we?
-What if this is--
-My niece drew it yesterday.
-Your niece…
-What?
No way Nobody would come
to a soba shop like this.
What's wrong with my shop?
I meant it in a good way.
So there's a spy amongst us?
Well…
…a soba place like this…
What I know for sure is,
you guys are being suspected.
Attention, please.
Euro Sky Airways flight 638 from Astoria
will arrive at Gate 24.
-Light.
-Here.
Man, you guys are lifesavers.
We can handle it from here.
-Ah, thank you, then.
-Yup.
Thank you.
-I'll take over.
-Okay.
Excuse me. Thank you.
What should we do?
What?
How do we know if there's a spy or not?
First, we should observe everyone closely.
Over here.
-Here you are.
-Thank you.
Fumio Kusamoto.
Must have been a long flight.
Man, I'm exhausted.
Thirteen hours from Astoria
to Japan! Thirteen hours!
In that time, I could make
a whole lithograph.
Ah, sorry, sorry.
I'm a painter.
A painter?
That's my manager.
‎JIM BROWN - MANAGER
Ah, those are all my tools of the trade,
so handle them with care.
-It's all right. Welcome back.
-Thanks.
I think I'll relax and soak
in a hot spring for a bit.
dozens of brushes, and many paintings too.
But not all of it is art supplies, right?
No, of course not.
Since there's so much, I'd like
to inspect these in another room.
Sure, go ahead.
Please take over.
Just over here.
-I'm sorry, we're doing a quick check.
-Hey, what?
-It won't be long.
-What?
Kayla Ferguson and Mimi Ferguson, right?
Yes.
Please wait a moment.
Um… You dropped this.
-Oh, whoa!
-Mimi, what's wrong?
-A-a-are you okay?
-Is something wrong?
I'm a doctor.
-Ah, a doctor…
-Let me take a look.
Stay still a second.
She seems to have
a slight fever. All right.
I'll contact the quarantine official.
Does it hurt anywhere?
-This is Endo from Gate 24.
-Are you feeling uncomfortable?
-There's a child who's not feeling well.
-Let's move you inside.
Chika?
There was a plane of passengers suspected
of having measles from Thailand,
so all the quarantine staff
got pulled away to deal with them.
-Could you wait a little longer?
-You'll speak with a doctor back here.
-Thank you.
-Just here.
Ah, over here.
It looks like it'll be a while
until human quarantine is available.
-Please bring the medical kit.
-Ah, yes.
-Ma'am, support her neck.
-Yes.
All right.
Thank you.
This might feel a bit cold.
-What's your name?
-Mimi.
Mimi? That's a cute name.
Will she be all right?
She might just be exhausted
from the flight.
She should recover after resting a bit.
You mentioned you're medical staff.
-Do you have any identification?
-Yes.
Kazuo Shirosaki.
That Kazuo Shirosaki?
Which one?
Excuse me.
Do you have any more ice packs?
-Yes.
Kazuo Shirosaki, 61 years old.
A member of the NPO "Saving Life"
that provides aid to areas
affected by emergencies.
Their work continues
to bring hope to people
affected by disasters and conflict.
It's true. He's amazing.
How much longer is this going to take?
We're almost finished.
Do you really need to take
this long? It's just art supplies.
It's regulation.
Fine, just hurry up.
What is this?
-Vanilla beans.
-Vanilla beans?
You mix them into the paint
to give it texture.
Haven't you checked enough?
I'm sorry, just a little longer.
I… I can't hold it anymore!
-This way!
-Just a little further!
-There, there!
-Right here!
-Here, here.
-Here, here, here.
He should've told us sooner
that his stomach hurt.
-Ah, Matsuyama.
-Yes?
-About his luggage…
-Ah,
it'd be bad if we both left, right?
Seike, please wait here.
No, that's not what I meant.
-Thank you for your help.
-It's nothing.
I used to live in Astoria too.
-Really?
-Yes,
three years ago.
Did you work at the airport
over there too?
No, I worked at a museum.
-The one in the old town area?
-Yes.
My daughter loved that museum.
Every time we went, it was spotless.
I polished it every day.
You did?
Yes.
Mr. Shirosaki?
She wants to talk to you.
What's wrong?
My tummy hurts.
Your stomach?
We apologize, operations
are temporarily suspended.
Please wait until we receive confirmation.
Hey, did something happen?
Where's Jim?
I'm sorry. Please wait a moment.
-What's going on?
-Multiple people have upset stomachs.
Excuse me.
The police have something to share.
We received an informal report
from the Astoria airport police.
A few hours ago, a food poisoning incident
broke out at the Astoria airport.
People who ate at airport restaurants
are reporting headaches and stomach pain
and are being rushed to hospitals.
-Whoa, that's crazy.
-That's terrible.
Considering the onset time,
passengers on the flight from Astoria
might experience the same symptoms.
Actually, people are already
showing symptoms.
Yes, right now, a seven-year-old girl
and a male in his thirties
are complaining of stomach pain.
So it's true then.
What's the cause?
They haven't identified it yet.
There are too many restaurants.
They don't know which one caused it.
If it's spoiled ingredients,
it's an accident,
but if someone intentionally
mixed something in,
it's a crime.
An accident or a crime…
We should check
on other passengers as well.
RAN FUKAZAWA - CHIEF HEARING OFFICER
How many passengers remain?
About another 15.
Halt all inspections for now.
Split up and check
the health of the passengers.
Move those who are clear
to the waiting area.
We also need to check those
who already cleared immigration.
-Yes. Notify all relevant divisions.
-Yes, sir.
-All right, we will contact Astoria again.
-Yes.
I'll notify the Counselor myself.
All right, let's go, go, go.
I am a quarantine official.
I will be asking you all
a few questions about your health.
If any of you are feeling ill,
please let us know immediately.
-Thank you very much.
-Please proceed over there.
-Please go on to the waiting area.
-Just over there.
You first, then.
HAND SANITIZER
He's the last one, then.
Ah, no…
I'll tell him.
I think I'm feeling a little better now.
That's good to hear.
A medical professional
is in a separate room,
-so we'll have you see him.
-Okay.
We'll bring your luggage there as well.
All right. Oh, dear.
I was supposed to fly back
to the UK tomorrow.
I see.
Sorry.
Huh…
What's wrong?
‎Nothing.
-So?
-Looks like he's healthy.
What happened?
Oh, no, nothing really.
-Hey, I wanted to ask you something.
-Yes?
My inspection's done, right?
Can I go get Jim's luggage?
Jim's luggage hasn't
finished inspection yet.
Yes. But the stuff inside belongs to me.
Even so, the owner who checked
the luggage must be present.
Yes, I understand,
but can't you make an exception?
I'm very sorry, but no.
What? Fine.
By-the-book bureaucrats.
I'll place your luggage here.
‎Thank you.
This man also seems to have stomach pain.
Would you mind taking a look at him?
Okay. Please take off
your shoes and lay down.
‎Okay.
Um… Matsuyama.
The art supplies in that suitcase
belong to Kusamoto, right?
Yes, that's what he said.
It's strange.
What is?
Kusamoto is Nobody, the anonymous artist.
-Huh?
-Nobody?
-For real?
-No, no, no…
-Hey, Mori, what are you talking about?
-Yes.
We were talking about it in the soba shop,
but there's no way
they'd actually be here now.
But it's the only thing that makes sense.
But I can't believe Nobody
is just a Japanese man…
Nobody is anonymous.
No reason he can't be Japanese.
-Do you have proof?
-Ah, yes.
Two days ago, a mural believed to be
painted by Nobody was discovered
on a building in downtown Astoria.
This.
The exact same drawing
was inside that sketchbook.
Huh…
Is that really him?
So he painted it two days ago in Astoria
and returned to Japan today?
The timing matches.
Isn't that a bit too wild
of an assumption?
Seike, you were the one
who inspected Kusamoto, right?
-Yes.
-Did you notice anything of interest?
-Of interest?
-If he really is Nobody,
he should have frequent travel
to politically unstable countries.
Well, I didn't look that far into him.
Must be tough though,
flying around the world
just to paint murals.
It seems he usually resides in the UK.
The UK?
Come to think of it, Jim mentioned he was
planning to return to the UK tomorrow.
That's strange.
Kusamoto said he planned to relax
at a Japanese hot spring for a while.
Their stories don't align.
Truly an anonymous painter.
His actions are mysterious too.
Could that rumor actually be true?
It's a rumor floating around online.
The theory that Nobody is a spy.
A spy?
The rumor says that though
he pretends to advocate
for the weak, he's actually
gathering military
and government intelligence
in conflict zones.
Oh, come on, don't believe such nonsense.
But wasn't there a theory that even
Matsuo Basho was actually a spy?
The Narrow Road to the Deep North.
Thinking like that, it makes sense why
he was in politically unstable Astoria.
Can we really just let
someone like that pass through?
But we don't have any concrete evidence.
Exactly.
Isn't it premature to assume
Kusamoto is Nobody?
Let's get back to work!
Let's go, go, go.
Mori, can I speak with you for a moment?
What Matsuyama mentioned
actually caught my attention.
Yes.
If Kusamoto is Nobody, as you say,
and if he's a spy, as Matsuyama says,
there may be someone
amongst us who's
in direct contact with him.
If there really is a spy in Gate 24,
it may be that person.
What are you doing?
What are you hiding?
I'm not hiding anything.
What did Kusamoto write in that notebook?
Kusamoto?
-What are you talking about?
-Stop playing dumb.
Seike,
you knew Kusamoto
was the anonymous artist, didn't you?
Seike.
You knew Kusamoto
was the anonymous artist, didn't you?
Seike.
I'm sorry.
I have
done something
an immigration official should never do.
This is…
Oh my.
What's this?
It's the autograph of
Nobody, the anonymous artist.
Nobody's autograph?
So you noticed he was Nobody, Seike?
Yes.
When I was inspecting Jim's luggage…
Thank you for waiting.
Could you please sign here?
By any chance, are you Nobody?
What?
What are you talking about?
Don't play dumb. You can't fool me.
Please keep this confidential.
So, in exchange for keeping quiet,
you got his autograph?
This is work!
What was the purpose
of establishing this gate again?
Sharing information
across Immigration and Customs.
Information sharing!
We shouldn't have to tell you that
at this point.
I'm sorry.
What a wild swing and a miss, huh?
Seike,
-you are an embarrassment!
-Hayami,
so there is a spy amongst us here?
Excuse me.
Oh, thank goodness.
It's from Chief Hearing Officer Fukazawa.
Hello. This is Seike.
What? Hey, everyone.
Regarding the food poisoning
at Astoria airport,
according to local police,
it's very likely some sort of poison
was scattered in an airport restaurant.
Poison?
It's a restaurant called Freedom.
Please ask each passenger whether they ate
at that restaurant.
-Yes!
-Yes.
Everyone, I'd like to ask
you all something.
-What? J-Jim, a-are you okay?
-Jim!
Jim, can you hear me?
Ventricular fibrillation.
-Bring me an AED.
-Okay!
Help me lower him to the flower.
-Here we go.
I understand.
One male passenger
has been transported to the hospital.
What's his condition?
Thanks to swift emergency treatment,
his life isn't in danger.
Ah, thank goodness.
But your gate is one trouble
-after another.
-Save the lecture for later.
Right now, understanding
the situation comes first.
I have a good idea of the situation.
This is most likely terrorism.
Terrorism?
Ever since the regime change
two years ago in Astoria,
an anti-government organization
called Wings of the People
has been committing
frequent acts of terror.
Wings of the People?
-Looking at the situation, it's likely--
-I'm not so sure about that.
At this stage, there's no evidence
linking this to that group.
-A restaurant called Freedom?
-Yes.
Did you eat there before departure?
No, I didn't.
We did. Why?
Um, it's possible
the food there was poisoned.
Is that why Mimi's sick?
But I ate there too.
Symptoms vary depending on the amount
consumed and your constitution.
So does that mean I…
You might not show symptoms,
but we shouldn't be overly optimistic.
Do you remember what you ate?
Uh, it was a buffet, so we ate
some salad, chicken…
-Excuse me.
-Yes?
Hey! Is it true Jim
was taken to the hospital?
Yes, his condition suddenly deteriorated.
He had stabilized briefly, but…
Then why?
A poison may have been scattered
at a restaurant called
Freedom in Astoria Airport.
-Poison?
-Yes.
That's why we need to ask you
some questions as well.
As you can see, I'm perfectly fine!
More importantly, which hospital
was Jim taken to?
I need to go to him right away.
I'll take those.
-Ah, no, no, you can't…
-Excuse me.
Then what do I do?
Leave them here until Jim gets back?
-No, um, like I said…
-Hey!
Shut up!
Don't take it out on a child!
Right now, your job
is to answer the questions.
You ate with Jim, didn't you?
Shirosaki.
I ate lunch
at a different restaurant.
Jim was the only one
who went to that place.
Satisfied?
Thank you for your cooperation.
Don't cry, don't cry.
It's okay now.
This isn't terrorism.
-What?
-I saw the news online.
They suspect it was caused
by the anti-government organization
Wings of the People.
But they aren't
an organization that
indiscriminately involves civilians.
If anything, we should suspect
the government.
Astoria is on the brink
of economic collapse
due to inflation.
Meanwhile, officials and politicians
line their pockets through corruption.
The public's frustration
has reached its limit.
Lives exist to be saved.
But in this world,
there are lives not worth saving.
Seeing the tragedy in Astoria
has made me feel that way.
Excuse me.
The man gave it to me.
By "the man", do you mean Jim?
Yes.
He gave you this at the restaurant, right?
-Yes.
-I'm sure.
I took a photo at the restaurant.
A photo?
-He handed her a napkin?
-Yes.
There's something I want to confirm.
I finally get those back, huh?
All right, let's get this
over with already.
Before that, we need to confirm something.
Checking again?
Are you really Nobody?
What?
What's that?
That girl, Mimi, got this from Jim.
From Jim? Why would he do that?
It seems he gave her this
at a restaurant called Freedom.
‎Hold on.
‎Here you are.
Alright, I'm sure you're starving, right?
I got a bunch.
Jim is the one who drew this. Not you.
In short, well, in other words,
you are the manager,
and the real Nobody is Jim.
-No way…
-What?
Their roles were reversed?
What?
I see! I see, I see.
That's funny, isn't it?
Nobody didn't want his identity known,
so he switched roles
of painter and manager with you.
Is that correct?
Would Nobody, who fights for the weak,
yell at a child like that?
No, um, like I said…
-Hey!
-Shut up!
That's also what drew our suspicion.
So what if that's true? Huh?
That's right.
He asked me to play Nobody for him.
I've been doing so for years now.
Is there a problem with that?
No.
That's not where the problem lies.
What?
This is the photo Mimi's mother took.
-Excuse me.
-Wait, wait…
This is you, isn't it?
Yes, that does seem to be me.
You said you didn't go to that restaurant
and that only Jim ate there.
-Why lie?
-No, it wasn't a lie.
Um, I'm sorry, you know,
I just
-misremembered, is all.
-Another strange thing.
Jim was rushed to the hospital
in critical condition.
And yet, you never once worried
about your own health.
So what?
It's almost as if you knew you wouldn't
be affected by the poison.
-Well, normally when you're sick--
-You are the one
who poisoned the food
at that restaurant, aren't you?
What?
Seriously?
What are you talking about?
That's not true!
The restaurant was a buffet.
The two who had stomach pain,
Jim and Mimi,
both had salads on their plates,
but you didn't take any salad.
-That's just a coincidence.
-Furthermore,
those are rubber gloves
sticking out of your pocket, right?
You used them to handle
the toxic substance, didn't you?
That's-- You-- You're pretty
stupid too, huh? That's not true!
That's all just speculation, isn't it?
Do you have proof? Huh?
If I have poison, then where is it?
You don't think it's inside there, do you?
May we inspect the luggage again?
What? You already looked, right?
Do what you want.
However,
if you don't find anything,
be prepared for the consequences.
-Be prepared!
-Okay.
‎Well then, I will check the contents.
-That's the last piece of luggage.
-This is nuts, isn't it?
Um… What's this?
Ah, those are vanilla beans.
They're used on paintbrushes.
Vanilla beans…
Jim said the same thing.
Miss?
Did you find the poison?
Well then…
You're all prepared, aren't you?
I recorded this whole thing.
I'll post online how airport staff
treated me like a criminal.
I look forward to seeing what happens.
I'm taking back my luggage now.
No objections to that, right?
No.
Um…
There's no smell.
What?
This white part, it isn't vanillin.
Vanillin?
Vanillin is where the smell comes from.
If this is vanillin,
it should smell like it.
-But--
-That's enough.
-Just close it already!
-What is that white part then?
-It's mold.
-Mold?
Certain molds that grow on vanilla beans
produce a toxic substance
called mycotoxin.
Meaning?
This is
the poison that hurt Jim, isn't it?
Eventually, the poison detected
in Jim's system will be identified.
If that matches the substance found
-in these vanilla beans--
-Damn it, you bastard!
Wait!
I'm kidding. It's a joke, it's a joke.
I'd never run.
All right…
Stop!
If you eat that,
you might destroy the evidence.
But that poison
causes acute liver failure.
And…
A-And?
You will die.
-You're bluffing.
-No. You will die.
-No, I won't!
-You will.
Damn it!
Yes!
‎I don't want to die!
What a big old mess.
Kusamoto had massive debts,
so it seems he was trying
to sell off Jim's artwork.
-So that's why he poisoned Jim?
-Yes.
But why would he drag
other people into it too?
If he went straight for Jim,
he'd be the first suspect.
So he tried to disguise it
as an indiscriminate attack.
That's so selfish.
You were right, Counselor.
At least this incident
wasn't terrorism
by an anti-government organization.
That's true.
It's true that mycotoxins
cause severe liver inflammation.
However, unless ingested
in massive quantities,
it's rarely fatal.
So what you said earlier…
-You will die.
-No, I won't!
You will.
Yes, it was a bluff.
Oh my.
But that bluff solved the case
and saved the culprit's life.
You are an amazing customs official.
Thank you very much.
So, what about Jim?
He received treatment at the hospital
and is recovering.
That's good to hear.
Now I can rest easy.
Dr. Shirosaki!
Mimi!
Thank you so much, Dr. Shirosaki.
Is Mimi okay?
Yes, but just to be sure,
we're heading to the hospital now.
She really wanted you to have this.
‎-Here.
‎-Huh?
Wow, you're good.
Thank you very much.
-Shall we head outside together?
-Sure.
Well then, I'll leave you here.
Yes.
Welcome home.
Let's go.
This is amazing, huh?
Nice colors.
‎I picked them.
To be honest, there's something
I haven't told you.
I was offered the chance
to return to headquarters
if I found the spy in Gate 24.
To say I wasn't tempted by the offer
would be a lie.
But I don't think there's
actually a spy in Gate 24.
No. Me neither.
So, I was actually the traitor.
I'm sorry for not telling you.
But you suspecting Seike
led to us solving the case.
So, after accounting for everything,
I say we're even.
You get some extra marks
for being honest with me.
Hey. Where are the passengers
from the Astoria flight?
Ah, they all cleared immigration?
Yes, the last one just left.
We were just a little too late.
What's the matter?
Didn't we solve the case?
No, this is a separate case.
Astoria airport police checked security
footage from the poison incident
and saw a member of Wings of the People
who boarded the flight to Japan.
A member of Wings of the People?
A man suspected of involvement
in the government facility bombing
six months ago
boarded the flight from Astoria.
But was there any Astorian
on the plane who was suspicious?
No, he's not Astorian.
He's Japanese.
This is him.
Hayami…
There's no way…
Shirosaki!
Kazuo Shirosaki, member of Wings
of the People, put the bag on the floor!
Shirosaki.
Shirosaki!
I have nothing to say.
Sorry.
What did you just take?
Hey!
Hurry! Water!
-Call an ambulance!
-Yes!
I saved…
lives all my life.
I'm glad I was…
able to save some more, in the end.
I understand.
Kazuo Shirosaki is unconscious
and in critical condition.
Why would Shirosaki
be in an anti-government group?
He lost his family
in a bombing incident
in Astoria's old town
a year ago.
His family?
Wait. Wasn't the bombing
done by the Wings of the People?
Some reports claim that bombing
was actually carried out
by the government itself.
They say it was a false flag operation
to crack down on dissidents.
That's horrible.
-Excuse me.
-Airport Director!
-Come in.
-Arima.
This is Kashiwagi, Cabinet Counselor,
and Arima from the Ministry of Justice.
What's everyone gathering here for?
Actually,
we found this among Kazuo Shirosaki's
personal belongings.
MIDORI SUGIHARA
The Counselor's business card?
We'll need you to hear
what we have to say about this.
You are suspected of having ties
to an anti-government organization.
‎FINAL EPISODE
‎The survival of the gate
‎also hangs on this.
‎You're going to get rid of Gate 24?
‎We received information that there's
‎an assasination plot at the airport.
‎May I see this a second?
‎It's strange.
‎SOS…
‎Is the wife in danger?
‎I need a favor.
‎Subtitle translation by: Maslin Friedman